Tim Pettersen

Senior Developer / Developer Advocate at Atlassian

Summary

I'm an engaged, detail-oriented software developer with excellent communication skills and a passion for API design and product integration. I have seven years of experience working with java and a broad range of related technologies working for one of the world's premiere vendors of tools for software teams: Atlassian Software.

Experience

Senior Developer / Senior Developer Advocate at Atlassian

March 2013 - Present

Aiding, abetting and growth hacking the Atlassian developer ecosystem.

Team Lead at Atlassian

February 2010 - February 2013 (3 years)

- * Bootstrapped Stash, a java enterprise-focused Git hosting product. Subsequently lead a team of four developers and shipped the 1.0 release in a compressed timeframe.
- * Developed a static analysis SPI for Stash, with a checkstyle implementation for automated checking of code quality and standards.
- * Presented regular "bootcamp" classes for new employees, teaching best practice for developing crossproduct integration features with respect to security, performance and user experience.
- * Enhanced JQL (Atlassian JIRA's Antlr-based DSL) by allowing ad-hoc querying of how code changes relate to JIRA issues.
- * Developed an Android application for interacting with JIRA from any Android handset.
- Lead a team of two developers to add Git hosting support to FishEye, shifting the product's focus from passive analysis to repository hosting and management.
- * Lead a team of four developers to rewrite FishEye and Crucible's Lucene-driven search functionality, dramatically improving performance and user experience.
- * Lead a team of three developers to build Unified Application Links, an embeddable integration library using open web authentication standards (OAuth and Basic Authentication) to facilitate communication between java web applications. UAL now underpins all integration features within the six major standalone products in the Atlassian suite.
- * Developed a CAPTCHA cracker based on Python and the Tesseract OCR engine with a high enough success rate to drive significant security fixes to a vulnerable product.

Visiting Research Associate

2013 - 2013 (less than a year)

Java Developer at Atlassian

January 2006 - February 2010 (4 years 1 month)

- * Gained extensive experience with popular version control systems (specifically Git, Hg, SVN, P4, CVS & ClearCase) working as a developer on Atlassian FishEye: a java web application for browsing and analysing source code.
- * Built rich integration features between JIRA, FishEye, Crucible and Perforce using the Atlassian OSGibased plugin system and Jersey (JSR-311) REST stack.
- * Implemented in-browser rendering of three-dimensional model data sourced from FishEye repositories.
- * Served as a developer on Atlassian's flagship product: JIRA, an immensely popular java web application for managing projects and tracking issues.
- * Honed my front-end skills working on Crucible, a java web application that facilitates peer code review by allowing developers to annotate code using a rich "Web 2.0" UI.

Education

University of New South Wales

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.), Information Technology, 2002 - 2006

Activities and Societies: Alpha Beta Gamma Delta Epsilon

NSBHS

1997 - 2002

Tim Pettersen

Senior Developer / Developer Advocate at Atlassian



Contact Tim on LinkedIn